* Students
    
    *   How it Works
        
    *   Order & Status

* Platform
    
    *   K-12
        * [Records Management
            
            Centralize, digitize, and securely send student and alumni credentials, from transcripts to verifications.](https://www.parchment.com/platform/k-12/)
        * [SENDedu
            
            Help students complete their applications faster with SENDedu powered by Parchment](https://www.parchment.com/platform/sendedu-powered-by-parchment/)
        
    *   Higher Education
        * [Issuing
            
            Streamline issuing with a single platform for every credential you need, from diplomas to digital badges.](https://www.parchment.com/platform/higher-education/issuing/)
        * [Admissions & Enrollment
            
            Expand your recruiting pool and admit best-fit students faster.](https://www.parchment.com/platform/higher-education/admissions-enrollment/)
        * [Student Mobility
            
            Create new pathways to completion and solve transfer and dual enrollment challenges.](https://www.parchment.com/platform/pathways-for-student-mobility/)
        
    *   Government
        * [Statewide Initiatives
            
            Create consistent ways to exchange credentials across every school in your state.](https://www.parchment.com/platform/government/statewide-initiatives/)
        * [High School Equivalency
            
            Streamline the process of issuing, ordering, and sharing of GED®, HiSET®, and HSED credentials.](https://www.parchment.com/platform/government/high-school-equivalency/)
        * [Licensure
            
            Save time processing credentials with simple, automated digital workflows.](https://www.parchment.com/platform/government/licensure/)
        * [Student Mobility
            
            Create new pathways to completion and solve transfer and dual enrollment challenges.](https://www.parchment.com/platform/pathways-for-student-mobility/)
        
    *   Workforce
        * [Solutions
            
            Securely exchange credentials with the largest network of academic and professional organizations.](https://www.parchment.com/platform/workforce/solutions/)
        * [Industries
            
            Create, send, and verify any credential with ease, whether you are upskilling or certifying employees.](https://www.parchment.com/platform/workforce/industries/)
        
    *   International
        * [Issuing
            
            Streamline issuing with a single platform for every credential you need, from diplomas to digital badges.](https://www.parchment.com/platform/international/global-issuing/)
        * [Admissions & Enrollment
            
            Simplify your institution’s document intake process, eliminate paperwork, and streamline communication with your applicants.](https://www.parchment.com/platform/international/global-admissions-enrollment/digitary-services-receiving/)
        * [Verifications
            
            Streamline and enhance your evaluation procedures, attracting top global talent effortlessly.](https://www.parchment.com/platform/international/global-verifications/digitary-services-via/)

* Pricing

* Company
    
    *   Resources

* Order & Status

* 
    
    * [
        
        US](https://www.parchment.com/privacy-policy/)
    * [
        
        AU](https://www.parchment.com/en-au/privacy-policy/)
    * [
        
        CA](https://www.parchment.com/en-ca/privacy-policy/)
    * [
        
        IE](https://www.parchment.com/en-ie/privacy-policy/)
    * [
        
        日本語](https://www.parchment.com/ja/)
    * [
        
        NZ](https://www.parchment.com/en-nz/privacy-policy/)
    * [
        
        SEA](https://www.parchment.com/en-sea/privacy-policy/)
    * [
        
        UK](https://www.parchment.com/en-gb/privacy-policy/)

Menu

Privacy Policy
==============

##### Last Updated: 06/24/2024

© 2024 Parchment, an Instructure company (“Parchment”) we take your privacy seriously. We have developed this Privacy Policy to clearly describe how we collect, use, and disclose your personal information as we provide our services and tools on or via this website, [www.parchment.com](https://www.parchment.com/), and its affiliated websites (“the Site”), and in the Parchment applications accessed via the Site, collectively referred to herein as “Services.” The Services include the electronic ordering, fulfillment, and delivery of academic credentials and data, including without limitation, transcripts and related admissions documents, diplomas, test score reports, certificates and certifications (collectively, “Credentials”) and the electronic awarding of Credentials.

**By accessing and using our Site, using the Services, or by clicking “I accept” prior to your registration on the Parchment Site, you consent to the collection, use and disclosure of personal information by Parchment as described in this Privacy Policy.** If you are acting on behalf of an academic institution, school district, state agency, public and private board, or non-academic private entity (“Member”), you agree that you have the authority to  bind the Member and that this Privacy Policy shall apply to personal data provided by or on behalf of Member for the Services.   If you are a Member, your use of the Services is also governed by the applicable agreement or terms entered into between you and Parchment, which includes applicable privacy-related provisions.

“Personal information” (whether or not capitalized) as used in this Privacy Policy means any information about an identified natural person or that could reasonably identify a natural person. Personal Information shall not include publicly available information from government records (unless otherwise specified by applicable law) or de-identified or aggregated consumer information, where such information is not considered personal information by applicable privacy legislation.

Parchment complies with its obligations under applicable privacy law, which may include private sector privacy legislation where personal information is collected directly from you. When obtaining personal information through Members in the course of providing Services to members, Parchment handles your personal information as required by its Members and in accordance with the privacy laws that apply to its members.  Those laws may include freedom of information legislation and education/school acts. In this Privacy Policy, “applicable privacy law” refers to the privacy laws that apply based on the type of service we are providing (whether as a direct service provider or outsourced service provider) and the jurisdiction in which we are processing the personal information.  If you have any questions about a Member’s privacy practices, please contact the applicable Member.

This Privacy Policy includes privacy notices based on your individual relationship with Parchment and is organized as follows:

GENERAL TERMS; PRIVACY POLICY

CCPA PRIVACY NOTICE FOR CALIFORNIA RESIDENTS

INTERNATIONAL TERMS FOR RESIDENTS IN THE EUROPEAN ECONOMIC AREA (“EEA”), UNITED KINGDOM (“UK”) OR SWITZERLAND

GENERAL TERMS; PRIVACY POLICY

The General Terms; Privacy Policy outlines in detail:

1. Personal Information we collect
2. How we use personal information
3. How we share personal information
4. How we store your personal information
5. Your choices about receiving email
6. How to access and update your personal information or preferences
7. How we protect your personal information
8. How we make updates to this policy
9. How to contact us for more information

**1\. Personal Information We Collect:**
----------------------------------------

### Information You Provide.

We collect information you choose to provide us through the Site or via email. For example, we obtain information when you create an account, complete a registration form or feedback form, contact us requesting information, purchase our Services, respond to a survey, contact a customer support representative, or opt-in to provide information to one or more of our affiliates through the Site.

This information may include:

* Contact information  and registration information for example, your name, email address, postal address, phone number
* Education information: including information about your institution (for example, a school’s name and address), and other education information (not sourced from Credentials, including college admissions information, and test scores (e.g. SAT, GRE, etc.), which may be collected if you choose to use certain admissions tools available through the Site.
* Identity Information: If requested by your school in order to correctly identify your Credentials, we may request additional personal information from you, which may include the full social security/insurance number or last four digits of your social security/insurance number.
* Profile Information, you choose to provide information associated with your discovery profile which may include a profile photo, educational background, personal background, test scores, extracurricular activities, work or internship history, awards/achievements, certain demographic information, such as contact information, race, ethnicity, or gender.  Provision of certain information such as race or ethnicity is optional and you can remove it at any time.
* **Transactional information**: billing and payment information, as well as details about your transactions.
* **Inquiries and feedback**: comments and questions you submit through customer service interactions with us.
* **Research or  survey information**: information you provide if you participate in a survey (including demographic and statistical information, educational and employment information, usage information, and feedback).

You can choose not to provide us with certain information, but then you may not be able to successfully use the Services or take full advantage of the features of our Site.

If you provide us personal information about others, or if others give us your information, we will only use that information for the specific reason for which it was provided to us. You should not provide us with information about others unless you have been expressly authorized by the other person to provide this information to us.

### Information We Get from Others.

We may also get information about you from other sources, for example, if you have agreed to share information with one of our partners for purposes of the electronic ordering, fulfillment, and delivery of academic credentials and data or other use related to the Services. The type of personal information collected from other sources is similar to the personal information outlined above under “Information You Enter”. We may add this to information we get from you in our Services.

We may combine other publicly available information, such as information related to the organization for which you work, with the personal information that you provide to us through our Services.

### Information We Get from Members.

We may also receive personal information from our Members, which are academic institutions, school districts, state agencies, public and private boards, and non-academic private entities. The type of personal information collected from our members is similar to the personal information outlined above under “Information You Enter” and may also include student contact information, student demographic information such as age and gender, and student records, such as grades, transcripts, class lists, student schedules, student identification codes, or student disciplinary records.

When we obtain your personal information indirectly from our Members, we rely on their lawful authority to collect and use your personal information and provide it to us so that we can provide you with Services on behalf of our Member. Our members are solely responsible for obtaining all required consents and authorizations from the relevant individuals and for satisfying all obligations or rights owed to the member’s data subjects under applicable privacy law. Parchment is not responsible for the privacy policies or practices of its members. Changes to Your Personal Information.

It is important that the personal information we hold about you is accurate and current.  Please let us know if your personal information changes during your relationship with us by updating your account information or emailing us at privacy@parchment.com.

**Automatic Collection of Information**

Like many websites on the Internet, we automatically gather certain non-personally identifiable information and store it in log files. This information may include,

* Device information and related identifiers: including your IP address,
* your IP address, browser type, and Internet connection speed, device IDs, characteristics, systems, mobile device’s service provider, platform type, advertising identifiers, operating system, and the city, state or country from which you accessed the Site.
* Usage information: When you use our Site we and our service providers collect and analyze information about your usage activity, such as referring and exit pages and URLs, the number of clicks, files you download, domain names, landing pages, pages viewed and the order of those pages, the amount of time spent on particular pages, the date and time you used the Site, error logs, language preferences, and other similar information.

We may employ the use of “cookies” in certain areas of our Site to collect the information above. We use this information to analyze trends, to administer the site, to track users’ activity on the site, and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may link this automatically collected data to other information we collect about you.

Technologies such as cookies, beacons, tags and scripts are used by Parchment and our partners, affiliates, or service providers. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the Site, tracking users’ movements around the Site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis.

### Cookies.

We may collect information using “cookies.” Cookies are small data files stored on the hard drive of your computer or mobile device by a website. We may use both session cookies (which expire once you close your web browser) and persistent cookies (which stay on your computer or mobile device until you delete them) to provide you with a more personal and interactive experience on the Site.

We use two broad categories of cookies: (1) first party cookies, served directly by us to your computer or mobile device, which we use to recognize your computer or mobile device when it revisits the Site; and (2) third party cookies, which are served by service providers on the Site, and can be used by such service providers to recognize your computer or mobile device when it visits other websites.

### [Cookies we use](https://www.parchment.com/cookie-policy/).

Our Site uses the following types of cookies for the purposes set out below:

|     |     |
| --- | --- |
| **Type of cookie** | **Purpose** |
| _Essential Cookies_ | These cookies are essential to provide you with services available through the Parchment Site and to enable you to use some of its features. Without these cookies, the services that you have asked for cannot be provided, and we only use these cookies to provide you with those services. This includes Session cookies. Session cookies allow a website to remember your actions during a browsing session and expire once you close your web browser. Session cookies may be used for a variety of purposes, such as remembering that you logged into one of our websites and enables payment where applicable. |
| _Functional Cookies_ | These cookies allow our Site to remember choices you make when you use the Site. The purpose of these cookies is to provide you with a more personal experience and to avoid you having to re-enter your preferences every time you visit the Site. |
| _Analytics and Performance Cookies_ | These cookies are used to collect information about traffic to the Parchment Site and how users use our Site and Services. The information gathered may include the number of visitors to our Site, the websites that referred them to our Site, the pages they visited on our Site, what time of day they visited our Site, whether they have visited our Site before, and other similar information.  We use this information to help operate our Site more efficiently, to gather broad demographic information, monitor the level of activity on our Site, and improve the Site. The information gathered does not identify any individual visitor. The information is aggregated and anonymous.<br><br>We use Google Analytics for this purpose. Google Analytics uses its own cookies. You can find out more information about Google Analytics cookies [here](https://developers.google.com/analytics/resources/concepts/gaConceptsCookies) and about how Google protects your data [here](http://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html).  You can prevent the use of Google Analytics relating to your use of our Site by downloading and installing the browser plugin available [here](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en-GB). |
| _Advertising or Marketing Cookies_ | These cookies are used to identify Site visitors that are either known or unknown to enhance the experience they have on our Site. These cookies allow us to provide content that is personalized to match visitors’ browsing or user history.<br><br>We use Marketo for marketing automation. You can find out more about their privacy policy and cookie policy here: [https://www.marketo.com/company/legal/](https://www.marketo.com/company/legal/).  You can prevent the use of Marketo relating to your use of our Site by disabling this cookie here: [https://documents.marketo.com/legal/cookies/](https://documents.marketo.com/legal/cookies/). |

### Disabling Cookies.

You can typically remove or reject cookies via your browser settings. In order to do this, follow the instructions provided by your browser (usually located within the “settings,” “help” “tools” or “edit” facility).  Many browsers are set to accept cookies until you change your settings.

Further information about cookies, including how to see what cookies have been set on your computer or mobile device and how to manage and delete them, visit [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

If you do not accept our cookies, you may experience some inconvenience in your use of our Site. For example, we may not be able to recognize your computer or mobile device and you may need to log in every time you visit our Site. However, declining cookies will not prevent you from transacting with us.

### Do Not Track Signals.

Some Internet browsers may be configured to send “Do Not Track” signals to the online services that you visit. We do not currently respond to do not track signals. To find out more about “Do Not Track,” please visit [www.allaboutdnt.com](https://www.allaboutdnt.com/).

**2\. Why do we collect your information and how is it used?**
--------------------------------------------------------------

### Personal or Institution Information.

Any personal information that we collect is used to

* provide our Services and develop new ones
* facilitate the provision of Services that you may order and any related transactions and to further operate and improve our Services,
* personalize your account,
* allow communication between Parchment (its affiliates and service providers) and you and to manage your account including to  send administrative or customer service related emails and respond to your requests,
* Conduct research including product and services surveys,
* Conduct advertising and marketing (including sending emails about upcoming products or services), when express consent has been given where required by applicable privacy law,
* as we believe necessary or appropriate (a) to comply with applicable laws; (b) to comply with lawful requests and legal process, including to respond to requests from public and government authorities; (c) to enforce our Privacy Policy and Terms of Use; and (d) to protect our rights, privacy, safety or property and that of you or others, and (e) to protect, investigate, and deter against fraudulent, harmful, unauthorized, unethical or illegal activity; (ix) to evaluate a merger, divestiture, restructuring, reorganization, dissolution or other sale or transfer or some or all of our assets;
* as otherwise described to you when collecting your personal information; and
* as otherwise required or permitted by applicable privacy law.

Under certain law, we only collect, use or disclose your personal information with your consent, which may be implied by your use of our Services with knowledge of how we use your personal information, unless we are required or permitted by law to obtain your personal information without consent. We will request your consent to use your personal information where required by law, such as where we use certain cookies or similar technologies or would like to send you certain marketing messages.  If we request your consent to use your personal information, you have the right to withdraw your consent any time in the manner indicated when we requested the consent or by contacting us at [https://support.parchment.com](https://support.parchment.com/).

### Sensitive Personal Information.

We do not collect and we ask that you do not send us or disclose any sensitive personal information (e.g. information related to racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or other beliefs, health, biometrics, or criminal background) on or through the Services, with the exception of certain services on the Site where some users may opt in to providing ethnicity in connection with using the service. If you send or disclose any sensitive personal information to us when you submit user generated content in our Services, you consent to our processing and use of such sensitive personal information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. If you do not consent to our processing and use of such sensitive personal information, you must not submit such user generated content in our Services.

### Anonymous and De-Identified Data.

We may create anonymous data from your personal information and other individuals whose personal information we collect. We make personal information into anonymous data by excluding information that makes the data personally identifiable to you.

We may use anonymous information in aggregate form to provide institutions with analytics on Credential exchange activity through the Services, including analysis to track where requests are coming from and going to, benchmarking information, and for any other lawful business purpose. Additionally, we may use anonymous information in aggregate form to provide users with certain admissions-related analytics. These analytics rely solely on aggregated, anonymized data, and do not include any data from the Credentials we process.

We may use a vendor to assist us in collecting and analyzing information as described below.

**3\. How we disclose your information?**
-----------------------------------------

Our business hinges on security and the trust you place in us. We take great care to ensure that your personally identifiable information is only disclosed in the following limited circumstances:

* Designated Institutions or Third Parties. When a student, academic institution, or other user uses our Services, we will access certain data, including personal information, and may transmit, fulfill, or otherwise disclose Credentials and related data to such other academic institutions or third parties as authorized by such user. The consent of a student-user’s parent may be required to submit a Credential request for non-postsecondary students under the age of 18. We will disclose certain information with the institutions from which we obtain your Credentials in order to fulfill your order.
* Service providers. We may also use other companies and individuals to perform supporting functions on our behalf for the institutions that we work with or for the various Services offered through the Site, such as account billing and processing. They handle data only in compliance with the terms of this Privacy Policy and will not be permitted to use the information collected from you for any purpose other than performing the support functions for Parchment. Prior to partnering with any third-party service provider, we contractually require these service providers to use the information only to provide the contracted services and to represent that their privacy and security practices meet our standards and comply with applicable privacy law.
* Affiliates. We may disclose your personal information to our wholly owned subsidiaries, and any corporate affiliates or business partners, if any, and which are under common control with Parchment, for purposes consistent with this Privacy Policy.
* Professional Advisors. We may disclose your personal information to professional advisors, such as lawyers, auditors, and insurers, where necessary in the course of the professional services they render to us.
* Academic Research. We may share anonymous data with researchers at academic institutions for academic research purposes, including the study of topics of relevance to the admissions process, college access, and labor market outcomes. Researchers and academic institutions are only permitted to handle such data in compliance with the terms of a restricted use agreement with Parchment; additionally, such academic institutions must be accredited and the research must be approved by the researching institution’s institutional review board (IRB), passing review of the methods proposed for research to ensure that they are ethical.
* Protection of rights. We may disclose your information if we believe that such action is appropriate to: (i) comply with law or any lawful requests and legal process, such as to respond to subpoenas or requests from government authorities, (ii) enforce the Terms of Use Agreement for the Site or this Privacy Policy, (iii) respond to claims that any information or content posted on our site or transmitted through the use of the Services violates the rights of any third party, or (iv) protect the rights, privacy, property, or personal safety of Parchment, its affiliates and employees, other Site users or others, or (v) protect, investigate, and deter against fraudulent, harmful, unauthorized, unethical or illegal activity.
* Business transfers. Parchment may transfer, or otherwise disclose your information to an acquirer, assignee or other successor entity in connection with the transfer or sale of all or substantially all of the equity, business, or assets of Parchment to which your information relates, or in connection with an actual or contemplated sale, merger, bankruptcy, reorganization, change in control, or other similar transaction. Following such business transfer, this Privacy Policy may be assumed by the acquirer, assignee, or other successor entity and/or modified or replaced, subject to the modification terms (see below), and the acquirer, assignee, or other successor entity will be responsible for compliance under such policy.
* Other Third-Parties. Parchment may disclose personal information to other third-parties without your consent where required or permitted by law, including without limitation where: (i) the information is public as permitted by law; (ii) it is reasonable for the purposes of investigating a breach of an agreement, or actual or suspected illegal activity; (iii) it is necessary to identify an individual who is injured, ill or deceased; or (iv) due to an emergency that threatens the life, health or security of an individual.

### International Data Transfer

We are headquartered in the United States and may have business partners or members in other countries, and your personal information may be transferred, in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy, to the United States or other locations outside of your state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction where privacy laws may not be as protective as those in your jurisdiction and where the personal information may be subject to access by or disclosure to foreign law enforcement and other authorities under the laws of those jurisdictions. Parchment currently stores or transfers your personal information, or utilizes service providers, in the following countries: the United States.

By contacting Parchment at [privacy@parchment.com](mailto:privacy@parchment.com), you may request information from Parchment on the specific jurisdictions in which Parchment and/or its service providers will process personal information, including how to access such information and who to contact about the specific privacy practices involving the personal information.

European Union users should read the important information provided here about transfer of personal information outside of the European Economic Area. Canadian users authorize the transfer of their personal information into the United States and elsewhere as directed and authorized by the Canadian user or Member to Parchment. Parchment will take all reasonable measures to ensure that the personal information will not be used, transferred, or disclosed for purposes not relevant to the purposes of its collection or as authorized by you or a Member.

**4\. Storage and Retention of Information**
--------------------------------------------

Once a Credential request has been fulfilled, Parchment does not retain such Credential, unless requested by the individual user, the sending institution, or the receiving institution, for the convenience of such user, or to meet our legal and contractual obligations. For example, it is Parchment’s policy to comply with the sending institution’s preferences until the Credential is delivered. After the Credential is delivered, Parchment follows the receiver’s preferences regarding the retention and analysis of the transmitted Credential. If an individual user requests Parchment retain their Credentials on their behalf, Parchment will comply with such request and maintain the Credentials on behalf of such user in their personal account. Similarly, if an institution requests that Parchment store Credentials in the Parchment credential library, Parchment will comply with such request and maintain the Credentials on behalf of such institution in its credential library, subject to the applicable agreement between such institution and Parchment.

We will retain your other information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you Services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. Personal information that is subject to an access request will be retained even if access is denied in accordance with applicable privacy laws until the requestor has exhausted all recourses and/or appeal mechanisms under such laws. Where personal information is no longer needed and the requests identified above have been complied with, the personal information will be securely destroyed or permanently anonymized or de-identified.

**5\. Your Rights and Choices**
-------------------------------

Access, Correction and Deletion of Information

Depending on your jurisdiction, you may have the right to make certain requests regarding your “personal information” or “personal data” and (as such terms are defined under applicable law, and collectively referred to herein as “personal information”). Specifically, you may have the right to ask us to:

* Inform you about the categories of personal information we collect or disclose about you; the categories of sources of such information; the business or commercial purpose for collecting your personal information; and the categories of third parties with whom we disclose personal information.
* Provide you access to and/or a copy of certain personal information we hold about you.
* Correct or update personal information we hold about you.
* Delete certain personal information we have about you.
* Provide you with information about the financial incentives that we offer to you, if any.
* Opt you out of the processing of your personal information for purposes of profiling in furtherance of decisions that produce legal or similarly significant effects, if applicable.

You can access, review, correct, update, or delete the information you provide Parchment by signing in to your account and accessing the Profile tab. Account holders may also contact us at [privacy@parchment.com](mailto:privacy@parchment.com) to accomplish the foregoing or if you have additional requests or questions. We will correct, update or delete any personal information we have about you, unless we are required to keep it by law. Please note that certain information may be exempt from such requests under applicable law. For example, we need to retain certain information in order to provide our services to you. We also need to take reasonable steps to verify your identity before responding to a request, which may include verifying your name and email address. Depending on your jurisdiction, you may be permitted to designate an authorized agent to submit certain requests on your behalf. In order for an authorized agent to be verified, you must provide the authorized agent with signed, written permission to make such requests or a power of attorney. We may also follow up with you to verify your identity before processing the authorized agent’s request.

If your personal information is provided to us by a Member (defined above), then we will contact the Member or direct you to contact the Member regarding any correction, update, or deletion requests by you. If you request that we delete your information, please note that your information may continue to reside in our backup systems. Where personal information is being used to make a decision about you, we will make every reasonable effort to ensure such information is accurate and complete. We will make corrections to your personal information when notified by our members and we ask you to correct and update your information as outlined above.

Subject to restrictions and exceptions under applicable privacy law, upon request we will provide you with access to your personal information as well as information about the collection, use and disclosure of your personal information and a listing of the individuals or organizations to which your information has been disclosed. Such requests should include sufficient information to allow us to locate the records that you are seeking. Reasonable fees may apply to access requests, where permitted under Applicable Privacy Laws. We will generally respond to access requests within 30 days, except where a longer period of reply or an extension is permitted under applicable privacy law. If access is denied, we will provide you with a written explanation in accordance with applicable privacy law. Depending on applicable law, you may have the right to appeal our decision to deny your request, if applicable. To exercise such an appeal right, please contract privacy@parchment.com.

Opt Out of Sale of Personal Information or Sharing or Processing of Personal Information for Targeted Advertising

Depending on your location, you may opt out of certain processing of your personal information, including for targeted advertising, under applicable law.  Targeted advertising is when we or our partners display ads to you based on your personal information that is collected across different businesses.

We and our advertising partners collect certain information from our visitors, such as device identifiers, cookies, advertising IDs, IP addresses and usage activity and use this information to deliver more relevant (targeted) ads to you and for related advertising activities. This activity is known as “sharing” or processing your personal information for targeted ads and may be considered “selling” your personal information under applicable law. Please note Parchment does not sell member data and/or education credential data and therefore such data is not applicable to the Sale of Personal Information or Sharing or Processing of Personal Information for Targeted Advertising. For information on disclosure please refer to “How we disclose your information?” section of this policy.

If you (or in California, your authorized agent) would like to opt out of our use or disclosure of your information for such purposes, you can follow the steps at [Your Privacy Choices](https://www.parchment.com/cookie-policy/).

Even if you opt out, you will still see advertising, it just may be less relevant to you,.   If you have enabled a legally recognized browser-based opt out preference signal (such as Global Privacy Control) on your browser, we recognize such preference in accordance and to the extent required by applicable law. You will need to turn this on for each browser you use.

Marketing Choices

We give you an opportunity to let us know your preference in terms of receiving promotional e-mail mail or telephone calls, including information on Parchment’s various Services, when you register for a service, provide us with your personal information, or when we send you e-mails. Parchment complies with applicable law with respect to such communications. If you choose not to accept this communication, you may not receive special offers that may be of value. This option applies to promotional communications only, as we may find it necessary to send you e-mail relating to the Services you have purchased, your account or your orders. You can opt-out of receiving these types of communications or access your personal information by clicking on an unsubscribe link at the bottom of each message or by contacting us at privacy@parchment.com. You may continue to receive service-related and other non-marketing messages.

If you have opted in to receive communication offered from third parties through Parchment, please contact each such party for information about their available opt-out procedures. We are unable to opt you out of third-party marketing programs.

Where we are required by law to collect your personal information, or where we need your personal information in order to provide the Services to you, if you do not provide this information when requested (or you later ask to delete it), we may not be able to provide you with the Services and may need to close your account.  We will tell you what information you must provide to receive the Services by designating it as required in the Services or through other appropriate means.

**6\. Security**
----------------

We use industry-standard technology designed to protect your information and all transmissions made through our Services, and take reasonable measures to protect the confidentiality, security and integrity of personally identifiable information collected on our Services.

If you create an account, you are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of your account password and for activity that occurs under your account credentials.  Please email us at privacy@parchment.com if there are any unauthorized uses of your account or other breaches of security.

**7\. Third Party Services**
----------------------------

Our Site includes links to other websites and services whose privacy practices may differ from those of Parchment. These links are not an endorsement, authorization, or representation that we are affiliated with that third party. We do not exercise control over third party websites or services and are not responsible for their actions. When you follow a link to a third-party website, you are no longer protected by our Privacy Policy. If you submit personal information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy policies. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy policy of any site you visit.

Some of our partners may utilize framing techniques to serve content to and from webpages accessible through our Site while preserving the look and feel of our site. Please be aware that you are providing your personal information to these third parties and not to Parchment.

If you opt in to provide information to a third party whose services may be introduced by Parchment (e.g., through a site that is not owned or controlled by Parchment), please be aware that such collection of information is governed by the privacy statement of such third party.

**8\. Blog**
------------

Our Site offers publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, please contact us at privacy@parchment.com. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

**9\. Testimonials**
--------------------

We may display personal testimonials of satisfied customers on our site in addition to other endorsements. With your consent we may post your testimonial along with your name.  If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, please contact us at [privacy@parchment.com](mailto:privacy@parchment.com).

**10\. Social Media Widgets**
-----------------------------

Our Site includes social media features, such as the Facebook Like button and widgets, such as the ShareThis button or interactive mini-programs that run on our Site. These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our Site, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing such feature.

**11\. Single Sign-On**
-----------------------

You can log in to our Site using sign-in services such as Facebook Connect or an Open ID provider. These services will authenticate your identity and provide you the option to share certain personal information with us, such as your name and email address, to pre-populate our sign-up form. Services like Facebook Connect give you the option to post information about your activities on this Site to your profile page to share with others within your network. If you connect to such services through our Site you authorize us to access, use and store the information that you agreed the services could provide to us based on your settings on that service. We will access, use and store that information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. You can revoke our access to the information you provide in this way at any time by amending the appropriate settings from within your account settings on the applicable service.

**12\. Children’s privacy**
---------------------------

Our Site is a general audience website and no portion of the Site is directed to children under the age of 13. We do not collect personally identifiable information from any person we know is a child under the age of 13.

Should we be alerted that we have inadvertently collected personally identifiable information from a child under the age of 13, we will take steps to immediately delete it.

We further do not knowingly permit children under the age of 18 to become registered members of our Site, or to use our Services without parental consent. Parchment does not knowingly collect or solicit personal information about children under 18, except with their parent’s consent.

If you are a resident of California and under the age of 18, you may remove any content that you have posted to our Site. In the event you cannot remove the content, you may request for Parchment to remove the content by contacting privacy @parchment.com. Please note that the removal of content or information from our Site does not ensure complete or comprehensive removal of the content or information posted on our Site.

**13\. Modifications**
----------------------

At Parchment, protecting your privacy is important to us. By accessing and using our Site, you consent to the collection, use and disclosure of information by Parchment as described in this Privacy Policy. We reserve the right to modify the Privacy Policy at any time. The “Last Updated” legend above indicates when this Privacy Policy was last modified. The revised Privacy Policy will become effective as of the date it is posted on the Parchment Site. We recommend that you to periodically review the Privacy Policy to ensure familiarity with the most current version. We may also notify you by email in the event of such material change. If you have any questions concerning this policy, please email us at privacy@parchment.com.

In all cases, your continued use of the Services after the posting of any modified Privacy Policy indicates your acceptance of the terms of the modified Privacy Policy.

**14\. Contact Us**
-------------------

We have a privacy officer to verse compliance with this Privacy Policy and how we handle personal information. If you have any questions or concerns at all about our Privacy Policy or to contact our privacy officer, please feel free to email us at [privacy@parchment.com](mailto:privacy@parchment.com) or write to us at:

© 2024 Parchment, an Instructure company

7001 N. Scottsdale Road, Suite 1050

Scottsdale, AZ 85253

Attn: General Counsel

If any concerns are not resolved to your satisfaction, you may contact the applicable privacy commissioner/regulator.

CCPA PRIVACY NOTICE FOR CALIFORNIA RESIDENTS  
PRIVACY NOTICE FOR CALIFORNIA RESIDENTS

Updated: 3/31/23

This Privacy Notice for California Residents supplements the information contained in the Privacy Policy of © 2024 Parchment, an Instructure company (“Parchment”) and applies solely to all visitors, users, and others who reside in the State of California (“consumers” or “you”). We adopt this notice to comply with the California Consumer Privacy Act of 2018 (CCPA) and any terms defined in the CCPA have the same meaning when used in this notice. Capitalized terms not otherwise defined in this Privacy Notice shall have the definitions set forth in the Privacy Policy. This Privacy Notice for California Residents supplements the Privacy Policy as indicated above and does not replace or otherwise modify the Parchment Privacy Policy.

Parchment does not knowingly collect personal information from California consumers under the age of 16.

**1) Information We Collect.** 

From Consumers Directly. Our Services (as defined in the Privacy Policy) may collect information directly from consumers, which identifies, relates to, describes, references, is capable of being associated with, or could reasonably be linked, directly or indirectly, with a particular consumer or device (“personal information”). This personal information may be collected directly from you on the Site (as defined in the Privacy Policy) or through the Services, or indirectly from you, for example by observing your actions in the Services or on the Site.

From Covered Businesses. Our Services may also collect such personal information about consumers indirectly from Members, such as an educational institution, district, school, or other type of organization that may be a covered business under the CCPA. In such event, Parchment is deemed an exempt third party as defined under the CCPA, that processes personal information on behalf of such covered business for business purposes of electronic ordering, fulfillment, and delivery of academic credentials and data. Such processing activities are governed by the contract between Parchment and such covered business and the Privacy Policy of such covered business. This Privacy Notice for California Residents shall not apply to personal information collected from covered businesses as set forth in this paragraph. Please see the privacy policy and notices from such covered business.

The Parchment Services have collected the following categories of personal information from its consumers within the last twelve (12) months:

|     |     |
| --- | --- |
| **Category** | **Examples** |
| Identifiers. | A real name, alias, postal address, unique personal identifier, online identifier, Internet Protocol address, and/or email address. |
| Personal information categories listed in the California Customer Records statute (Cal. Civ. Code § 1798.80(e)). | A name, signature, address, telephone number, education, employment, or employment history.<br><br>Some personal information included in this category may overlap with other categories. |
| Protected classification characteristics under California or federal law. | Age (40 years or older),  or gender. |
| Commercial information. | Records of products or services purchased, obtained, or considered. |
| Internet or other similar network activity. | Browsing history, search history, information on a consumer’s interaction with a website, application, or advertisement. |
| Non-public education information (per the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (20 U.S.C. Section 1232g, 34 C.F.R. Part 99)). | Education records directly related to a student maintained by an educational institution or party acting on its behalf, such as grades, transcripts, class lists, student schedules, student identification codes, or student disciplinary records. |

‌Personal information does _not_ include:

1. Publicly available information from government records.
2. De-identified or aggregated consumer information.
3. Information excluded from the scope of the CCPA.

**2) Use of Personal Information; Business Purpose.** We may use, or disclose the personal information we collect for one or more of the purposes set forth above, which includes without limitation, to fulfill or meet the reason you provided the personal information to Parchment, contact you; to analyze the use of our Services; to market our Services to you; for security; for legal compliance; and with your consent.

Parchment may sell, transfer, or otherwise share your personal information to an acquirer, assignee, or other successor entity in connection with the transfer or sale of all or substantially all of the equity, business, or assets of Parchment to which your personal information relates or in connection with a sale, merger, bankruptcy, reorganization, change in control or similar transaction. Following such business transfer, this Privacy Notice and the Privacy Policy may be assumed by the acquirer, assignee, or other successor entity and/or modified or replaced, subject to the modification terms of the Privacy Policy and applicable law, and the acquirer, assignee, or other successor entity will be responsible for compliance under this Privacy Notice.

**3) Disclosing Personal Information; Categories of Third Parties**.

Parchment may disclose your personal information to a third party for a business purpose as outlined in this Privacy Notice and our Privacy Policy, including Designated Institutions or Third Parties; Service Providers; Professional Advisors; Academic Research; Protection of Rights; Business Transfer; social media services pursuant to your integration and settings; and with your consent.

The information we have disclosed in the preceding 12 months to the above entities includes the following categories of information from Section 1 above:

Identifiers,  California Customer Records personal information categories, Protected classification characteristics under California or federal law, Commercial information, Non-public education information, See “How do we share your information?” for more details.

**4) Your Rights and Choices.**

The CCPA provides consumers (California residents) with specific rights regarding their personal information. See your rights and choices above.

Opt Out of Sale of Personal Information or Sharing of Personal Information for Targeted Advertising

You may opt out of certain processing of your personal information, including for targeted advertising, under applicable law.

We and our advertising partners collect certain information from our visitors, such as device identifiers, cookies, advertising IDs, IP addresses and usage activity and use this information to deliver more relevant (targeted) ads to you and for related advertising activities. This activity is known as “sharing” your personal information for targeted ads and may be considered “selling” your personal information under applicable law.  Please note Parchment does not sell member data and/or education credential data and therefore such data is not applicable to the Sale of Personal Information or Sharing or Processing of Personal Information for Targeted Advertising. For information on disclosure please refer to “How we disclose your information?” section of this policy.

If you (or your authorized agent) would like to opt out of our use or disclosure of your information for such purposes, you can follow the steps at [Your Privacy Choices](https://www.parchment.com/cookie-policy/).   You will need do this on for each browser you use.

Even if you opt out, you will still see advertising, it just may be less relevant to you.

**Non-Discrimination.**

We will not discriminate against you for exercising any of your CCPA rights.

**Other California Privacy Rights.**

California’s “Shine the Light” law (Civil Code Section § 1798.83) permits users of our Services that are California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. Parchment does not disclose personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. For more information, please send an email to [privacy@parchment.com](mailto:privacy@parchment.com).

**5) Changes to Our Privacy Notice.** 

Parchment reserves the right to amend this privacy notice at our discretion and at any time. When we make changes to this privacy notice, we will post the updated notice on the Website and update the notice’s effective date. Your continued use of our Site and/or the Parchment Services following the posting of changes constitutes your acceptance of such changes.

**6) Contact Information.** 

If you have any questions or comments about this notice, the ways in which Parchment collects and uses your information described below and in the Privacy Policy, your choices and rights regarding such use, or wish to exercise your rights under California law, please do not hesitate to contact us at:

**Phone**: (844) 515-2272  
**Website**: www.parchment.com  
**Email**: privacy@parchment.com

**INTERNATIONAL TERMS FOR RESIDENTS IN THE EUROPEAN ECONOMIC AREA (“EEA”), UNITED KINGDOM (“UK”) OR SWITZERLAND**

Parchment may receive personal information from individuals that visit or Site and that we receive in the United States from the EEA, UK, or Switzerland (referred to herein as “EEA, UK, or Swiss personal information.” Our Privacy Policy governs Parchment’s collection and use of such EEA, UK, or Swiss personal information and is supplemented by these international terms. These international terms supplement and do not replace or modify the Parchment Privacy Policy.

Parchment is based in and operates in the United States.  As a result, we and our service providers will process personal information in the United States and in other locations outside of the European Economic Area, where there may be different data protection standards than in the EEA.  By using the Services, you acknowledge that personal information will be processed in outside of the EEA.

**Data Privacy Framework**

Parchment complies with the EU-U.S. Data Privacy Framework (“**EU-U.S. DPF**”), the UK Extension to the EU-U.S. DPF, and the Swiss-U.S. Data Privacy Framework (“**Swiss-U.S. DPF**”), as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce. Parchment is certified to the U.S. Department of Commerce that it adheres to the EU-U.S. Data Privacy Framework Principles (“**EU-U.S. DPF Principles**”) with regard to the processing of personal data received from the European Union in reliance on the EU-U.S. DPF and from the United Kingdom (and Gibraltar) in reliance on the UK Extension to the EU-U.S. DPF. Parchment has certified to the U.S. Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Swiss-U.S. Data Privacy Framework Principles (“**Swiss-U.S. DPF Principles**”) with regard to the processing of personal data received from Switzerland in reliance on the Swiss-U.S. DPF. If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the EU-U.S. DPF Principles and/or the Swiss-U.S. DPF Principles, the Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Data Privacy Framework (“**DPF**”) program, and to view our certification, please visit https://www.dataprivacyframework.gov/.

Parchment commits to subject to the EU-U.S. DPF Principles and the Swiss-U.S. DPF Principles (collectively, “**DPF Principles**”) all personal data received from the EU, UK, and Switzerland in reliance on the relevant DPF.

Parchment is accountable for the processing of personal data it receives under the DPF Principles and subsequently transfers to a third party. Parchment complies with the DPF Principles for all onward transfers of personal data from the EU, UK, and Switzerland, including the onward transfer liability provisions. The Federal Trade Commission has jurisdiction over Parchment’s compliance with the EU-U.S. DPF, UK Extension to the EU-U.S. DPF, and the Swiss-U.S. DPF.

Parchment may be required to disclose personal data in response to law requests by public authorities, including to meet national security and law enforcement requirements.

Residents of the EU, UK, and Switzerland have the right to access the personal data that Parchment maintains, and in some cases, have choices to limit the use and disclosure of personal data. To the extent required by the EU-U.S. DPF Principles and the Swiss-U.S. DPF Principles, Parchment will offer individuals the opportunity to opt-out when personal data is (a) to be disclosed to certain third parties, or (b) to be used for a purpose that is materially different from the purpose for which it was originally collected or subsequently authorized by the individual. These rights are described more fully in the “Your Rights and Choices” section of this Privacy Policy. To exercise these rights, contact us at [privacy@parchment.com](mailto:privacy@parchment.com).

In compliance with the EU-U.S. DPF, the UK Extension to the EU-U.S. DPF, and the Swiss-U.S. DPF, Parchment commits to resolve DPF Principles-related complaints about our collection and use of your personal information. EU, UK, and Swiss individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding our handling of personal data received in reliance on the EU-U.S. DPF, the UK Extension to the EU-U.S. DPF, and the Swiss-U.S. DPF should first contact Parchment as described in the “Contact Us” section above.

In compliance with the EU-U.S. DPF, the UK Extension to the EU-U.S. DPF, and the Swiss-U.S. DPF, Parchment commits to refer unresolved complaints concerning our handling of personal data received in reliance on the EU-U.S. DPF, the UK Extension to the EU-U.S. DPF, and the Swiss-U.S. DPF to TRUSTe, an alternative dispute resolution provider based in the United States. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your DPF Principles-related complaint from us, or if we have not addressed your DPF Principles-related complaint to your satisfaction, please visit https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request for more information or to file a complaint. The services of TRUSTe are provided at no cost to you. Under certain conditions, more fully described on the [DPF website](https://www.dataprivacyframework.gov/framework-article/ANNEX-I-introduction), you may be entitled to invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted.

Students

* Login
    * US Student / Parent
    * Non-US Student
    * Admins

Platform

* K-12
* Higher Education
* Government
* Workforce

Products

K-12 Records Management

Higher Education

Statewide Initiatives

High School Equivalency

Licensure

Workforce

Company

* Pricing
* Resources

[Your Privacy Choices](https://www.parchment.com/cookie-policy/)| [Privacy Policy](https://www.parchment.com/privacy-policy/)| [Terms of Use](https://www.parchment.com/terms-of-use/) | © 2024 Parchment, an Instructure company

* [ ]  Students
* [ ]  Platform
* [ ]  Pricing
* [ ]  Company
[Book a Demo](https://www.parchment.com/book-a-demo/)* [ ]  Order & Status

Students

* [ ]  How it Works
* [ ]  Order & Status

Platform

* [ ]  K-12
* [ ]  Higher Education
* [ ]  Government
* [ ]  Workforce
* [ ]  International

Pricing

Company

* [ ]  Resources

Order & Status

* 

* 

* 

* 

* 

* 

* 

* 

We use cookies on our website to give you the most relevant experience by remembering your preferences and repeat visits. By clicking “Accept”, you consent to the use of ALL the cookies.  

Do not sell my personal information.

Cookie settingsACCEPT

Manage consent

Close

#### Privacy Overview

This website uses cookies to improve your experience while you navigate through the website. Out of these cookies, the cookies that are categorized as necessary are stored on your browser as they are essential for the working of basic functionalities of the website. We also use third-party cookies that help us analyze and understand how you use this website. These cookies will be stored in your browser only with your consent. You also have the option to opt-out of these cookies. But opting out of some of these cookies may have an effect on your browsing experience.

Functional

 Functional

Always Enabled

Functional cookies help to perform certain functionalities like sharing the content of the website on social media platforms, collect feedbacks, and other third-party features.

| Cookie | Duration | Description |
| --- | --- | --- |
| \_\_cf\_bm | 30 minutes | This cookie, set by Cloudflare, is used to support Cloudflare Bot Management. |
| \_\_sharethis\_cookie\_test\_\_ | session | ShareThis sets this cookie to track which pages are being shared and by whom. |
| bcookie | 1 year | LinkedIn sets this cookie from LinkedIn share buttons and ad tags to recognize browser ID. |
| bscookie | 1 year | LinkedIn sets this cookie to store performed actions on the website. |
| lang | session | LinkedIn sets this cookie to remember a user's language setting. |
| li\_gc | 5 months 27 days | This is a cookie from LinkedIn and is used for storing visitors' consent regarding the use of cookies for non-essential purposes |
| lidc | 1 day | LinkedIn sets the lidc cookie to facilitate data center selection. |
| liveagent\_oref | 1 year | This cookie is set by LiveAgent to allow Live Chat assistance for existing customers. |
| liveagent\_ptid | 1 year | LiveAgent sets this cookie to link previous chats and transcripts from a single visitor. |
| liveagent\_sid | session | LiveAgent sets this cookie to capture a unique pseudonymous ID when a user requests a chat during an active session. |
| liveagent\_vc | 1 year | This cookie is set by LiveAgent to allow Live Chat assistance for existing customers. |
| NextPage | past | This cookie tracks the previous page to allow users to go back and forth between pages using the user interface buttons. |
| UserMatchHistory | 1 month | LinkedIn sets this cookie for LinkedIn Ads ID syncing. |
| X-Salesforce-CHAT | session | This cookie is set by LiveAgent to allow Live Chat assistance for existing customers. |

Necessary

 Necessary

Always Enabled

Necessary cookies are absolutely essential for the website to function properly. These cookies ensure basic functionalities and security features of the website, anonymously.

| Cookie | Duration | Description |
| --- | --- | --- |
| aka\_debug | session | Vimeo sets this cookie which is essential for the website to play video functionality. |
| BIGipServer\* | session | Marketo sets this cookie to collect information about the user's online activity and build a profile about their interests to provide advertisements relevant to the user. |
| cookielawinfo-checkbox-analytics | 11 months | This cookie is set by GDPR Cookie Consent plugin. The cookie is used to store the user consent for the cookies in the category "Analytics". |
| cookielawinfo-checkbox-essential | 1 year | The cookie is set by the GDPR Cookie Consent plugin to record the user consent for the cookies in the category “Necessary”. |
| cookielawinfo-checkbox-functional | 11 months | The cookie is set by GDPR cookie consent to record the user consent for the cookies in the category "Functional". |
| cookielawinfo-checkbox-necessary | 11 months | This cookie is set by GDPR Cookie Consent plugin. The cookies is used to store the user consent for the cookies in the category "Necessary". |
| cookielawinfo-checkbox-others | 11 months | This cookie is set by GDPR Cookie Consent plugin. The cookie is used to store the user consent for the cookies in the category "Other. |
| cookielawinfo-checkbox-performance | 11 months | This cookie is set by GDPR Cookie Consent plugin. The cookie is used to store the user consent for the cookies in the category "Performance". |
| CookieLawInfoConsent | 1 year | CookieYes sets this cookie to record the default button state of the corresponding category and the status of CCPA. It works only in coordination with the primary cookie. |
| STYXKEY\_api\_token | 1 hour | AWS Cloud API |
| viewed\_cookie\_policy | 11 months | The cookie is set by the GDPR Cookie Consent plugin and is used to store whether or not user has consented to the use of cookies. It does not store any personal data. |
| vuid | 2 years | Vimeo installs this cookie to collect tracking information by setting a unique ID to embed videos to the website. |
| webinarVideo | never | Recursive support screen share session tracking cookie |

Performance

 performance

Performance cookies are used to understand and analyze the key performance indexes of the website which helps in delivering a better user experience for the visitors.

| Cookie | Duration | Description |
| --- | --- | --- |
| \_\_jid | 30 minutes | Cookie used to remember the user's Disqus login credentials across websites that use Disqus. |
| AWSALB | 7 days | AWSALB is an application load balancer cookie set by Amazon Web Services to map the session to the target. |

Essential

 essential

Analytics

 analytics

Analytical cookies are used to understand how visitors interact with the website. These cookies help provide information on metrics the number of visitors, bounce rate, traffic source, etc.

| Cookie | Duration | Description |
| --- | --- | --- |
| \_clck | 1 year | Persists the Clarity User ID and preferences, unique to that site, on the browser. This ensures that behavior in subsequent visits to the same site will be attributed to the same user ID. |
| \_clsk | session | Connects multiple page views by a user into a single Clarity session recording. |
| \_ga | 2 years | The \_ga cookie, installed by Google Analytics, calculates visitor, session and campaign data and also keeps track of site usage for the site's analytics report. The cookie stores information anonymously and assigns a randomly generated number to recognize unique visitors. |
| \_ga\_\* | 1 year 1 month 4 days | Google Analytics sets this cookie to store and count page views. |
| \_ga\_N0Q7GW0J6L | 2 years | This cookie is installed by Google Analytics. |
| \_gat\_gtag\_UA\_335339\_11 | 2 hours | Set by Google to distinguish users. |
| \_gat\_UA-\* | 1 minute | Google Analytics sets this cookie for user behaviour tracking. |
| \_gat\_UA-335339-11 | 1 minute | A variation of the \_gat cookie set by Google Analytics and Google Tag Manager to allow website owners to track visitor behaviour and measure site performance. The pattern element in the name contains the unique identity number of the account or website it relates to. |
| \_gcl\_au | 3 months | Provided by Google Tag Manager to experiment advertisement efficiency of websites using their services. |
| \_gid | 1 day | Installed by Google Analytics, \_gid cookie stores information on how visitors use a website, while also creating an analytics report of the website's performance. Some of the data that are collected include the number of visitors, their source, and the pages they visit anonymously. |
| AnalyticsSyncHistory | 1 month | No description |
| ANONCHK | 10 minutes | The Microsoft Clarity ANONCHK cookie, indicates whether MUID is transferred to ANID, which is a cookie used for advertising. Clarity doesn't use ANID and so this is always set to 0 indicating not for advertising. |
| CLID | 1 year | Used by Microsoft Clarity. The cookie is set by embedded Microsoft Clarity scripts. The purpose of this cookie is for heatmap and session recording. |
| CONSENT | 2 years | YouTube sets this cookie via embedded youtube-videos and registers anonymous statistical data. |
| disqus\_unique | 1 year | Set by Disqus to record internal statistics for anonymous visitors. |
| loglevel | never | Collects data on visitor interaction with the website's video-content - This data is used to make the website's video-content more relevant towards the visitor. |
| SM  | session | This Microsoft Clarity cookie is used in synchronizing the MUID across Microsoft domains. |
| SRM\_B | 1 year 24 days | Used by Microsoft Clarity as a unique ID for visitors. |
| ti\_ | 2 years | This cookie is set by Triblio to track the way a visitor uses the website and to monitor the performance of marketing campaigns. |
| VISITOR\_PRIVACY\_METADATA | 5 months 27 days | YouTube meta data |

Advertisement

 advertisement

Advertisement cookies are used to provide visitors with relevant ads and marketing campaigns. These cookies track visitors across websites and collect information to provide customized ads.

| Cookie | Duration | Description |
| --- | --- | --- |
| \_fbp | 3 months | This cookie is set by Facebook to display advertisements when either on Facebook or on a digital platform powered by Facebook advertising, after visiting the website. |
| bito | 1 year 1 month | This cookie is set by Beeswax for advertisement purposes. |
| bitoIsSecure | 1 year 1 month | Beeswax sets this cookie for targeting and advertising. The cookie is used to serve the user with relevant advertisements based on real time bidding. |
| fr  | 3 months | Facebook sets this cookie to show relevant advertisements to users by tracking user behaviour across the web, on sites that have Facebook pixel or Facebook social plugin. |
| IDE | 1 year 24 days | Google DoubleClick IDE cookies are used to store information about how the user uses the website to present them with relevant ads and according to the user profile. |
| MUID | 1 year 24 days | Bing sets this cookie to recognize unique web browsers visiting Microsoft sites. This cookie is used for advertising, site analytics, and other operations. |
| NID | 6 months | Google sets the cookie for advertising purposes; to limit the number of times the user sees an ad, to unwanted mute ads, and to measure the effectiveness of ads. |
| S   | 1 hour | Used by Yahoo to provide ads, content or analytics. |
| test\_cookie | 15 minutes | The test\_cookie is set by doubleclick.net and is used to determine if the user's browser supports cookies. |
| tuuid | 2 years | The tuuid cookie, set by Demandbase via BidSwitch, stores an unique ID to determine what adverts the users have seen if they have visited any of the advertiser's websites. The information is used to decide when and how often users will see a certain banner. |
| tuuid\_lu | 2 years | This cookie, set by Demandbase via BidSwitch, stores a unique ID to determine what adverts the users have seen while visiting an advertiser's website. This information is then used to understand when and how often users will see a certain banner. |
| VISITOR\_INFO1\_LIVE | 5 months 27 days | A cookie set by YouTube to measure bandwidth that determines whether the user gets the new or old player interface. |
| YSC | session | YSC cookie is set by Youtube and is used to track the views of embedded videos on Youtube pages. |
| yt-remote-connected-devices | never | YouTube sets this cookie to store the video preferences of the user using embedded YouTube video. |
| yt-remote-device-id | never | YouTube sets this cookie to store the video preferences of the user using embedded YouTube video. |
| yt.innertube::nextId | never | This cookie, set by YouTube, registers a unique ID to store data on what videos from YouTube the user has seen. |
| yt.innertube::requests | never | This cookie, set by YouTube, registers a unique ID to store data on what videos from YouTube the user has seen. |

Others

 others

Other uncategorized cookies are those that are being analyzed and have not been classified into a category as yet.

| Cookie | Duration | Description |
| --- | --- | --- |
| \_\_q\_state\_ajAThxcaogd4A5og | 1 year 1 month 4 days | Description is currently not available. |
| COMPASS | 1 hour | Description is currently not available. |

Save & Accept

Powered by [](https://www.cookieyes.com/)

This site is registered on [wpml.org](https://wpml.org/) as a development site. Switch to a production site key to [remove this banner](https://wpml.org/faq/how-to-remove-the-this-site-is-registered-on-wpml-org-as-a-development-site-notice/).
